

# **Zachary Branson**

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

**Phone:** (936) 676-5542

Address: 12106 Jamie Dr. Manor Tx, 78653

**Email:** zac21261@gmail.com **Website:** zacharybranson.com

**GitHub:** https://github.com/zac1127

### **PROFILE**

I am 25 years old, and currently a Senior Software Developer at Mattersight. I have been married to my wife Danica, and we recently had our first child Emma. I am a hard-working, detailed programmer, looking for new opportunities to use my skills and expand my knowledge as a software engineer.

Making Responsive, and interactive websites has been a passion of mine since a very young age. Every new web application I make, my goal is to make sure it is better than the last. I would love the opportunity to work, learn, and gain more knowledge and experience at your organization.

Thank you for taking the time to consider me for the open position.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Mattersight**

Apr 2018 - Present

#### **Senior Software Developer**

I currently work on a team with goals to improve and maintain a large-scale web application. I had the opportunity to work on major projects that improved the functionality and performance of the product. I worked as a full stack developer, with responsibilities that scaled from frontend to backend, and database management.

# **Mattersight**

Jun 2017 - Apr 2018

#### Software Developer

I currently work on a team with goals to improve and maintain a large-scale web application. I had the opportunity to work on major projects that improved the functionality and performance of the product. I worked as a full stack developer, with responsibilities that scaled from frontend to backend, and database management.

# **Elevation Church**

Feb 2017 - Jun 2017

#### Web Application Developer (contract position)

Built and maintained a social media like mobile application for staff to track fitness, nutrition, and bible studies. Users have the ability post achievements, add profile pictures, and comment on posts. I built using the Laravel PHP framework with a MySQL backend. I used HTML, CSS, and JQuery for the front-end development.



#### **Web Developer**

#### **Software Developer**

#### **Other**

- HTML
- PHP
- Java
- OOP
- Jenkins Git

- CSS
- Laravel
- **-** (
- COBOL

- JavaScript
- MySOL
- **C++**

Postman

- JOuery
- SQL Server
- Visual Basic

### **EDUCATION**



- Stephen F. Austin State University, Nacogdoches, Texas
- ABET (Accreditation Board for Engineering and Technology)
  Accredited University, <a href="http://www.abet.org/">http://www.abet.org/</a>
- Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

# **REFERENCES**

### Doug Standley (936) 414-6534

#### M&A advisor at Fleet Ridge Pacific

Fleet Ridge Pacific is a company that handles critical issues surrounding mergers and acquisitions in the healthcare industry.

# Dr. Jerry Spann

(936) 676-2691

#### Lead Pastor at Lufkin First Church of the Nazarene

Dr. Jerry Spann recently took the position of pastor of Lufkin First Church of the Nazarene. He previously founded LOVE Inc., a non-profit organization that helps churches expand their reach in the community, linking people with needs to church volunteers who have the resources to help.